Finding Aid for the Buddy Collette papers LSC.2458
UCLA Library Special Collections
Buddy Collette papers
1944-2008
UCLA Library Special Collections
Collette, Cheryl
LSC.2458
24.6 linear feet (26 boxes, 8 flat boxes, 8 record cartons, 1 map folder)
464 audiovisual carriers (112 open-reel audiotapes, 267 audiocassettes, 85 videocassettes)
24 born-digital carriers (21 optical discs, 3 DATs)
William Marcel "Buddy" Collette (1921-2010) was an American jazz musician, composer, and educator who performed on flute, saxophone, and clarinet and was active primarily in Los Angeles. A founding member of the Chico Hamilton Quintet, Collette began his musical career in high school and further developed his professional practice during his service as a band leader in the U.S. Navy during World War II. The collection spans approximately the 1940s through the early 2000s and documents Collette's professional career and creative output. Materials include correspondence and personal papers; musical works in manuscript and published formats; writings and other creative materials; printed and ephemeral materials; photographs; and audiovisual and born-digital materials. Audiovisual and digital materials document studio and live performances, film and television work, interviews, instructional recordings, and educational and community activities. The collection documents Collette's contributions to jazz performance, composition, and music education, as well as his professional networks within the Los Angeles music community.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIO/AUDIOVISUAL/DIGITAL MATERIALS: Audio/audiovisual/digital materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email AskLSC@library.ucla.edu.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Cheryl Collette, 2024.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9997248398406533
Biographical / Historical
William Marcel "Buddy" Collette (1921-2010) was an American jazz musician, composer, arranger, educator, and labor activist based in Los Angeles. Born and raised in the Watts neighborhood, Collette began performing professionally at fifteen while still in high school and was part of a close-knit community of musicians that included Charles Mingus and the Woodman brothers. He developed early proficiency on the saxophone, clarinet, and flute. During World War II, Collette served in the United States Navy as a bandsman and bandleader, developing his skills as a composer and arranger as they often needed new material to play. Following his discharge in 1945, he became an active participant in the postwar Los Angeles jazz scene, performing with prominent big bands and small ensembles and establishing himself as a studio musician.In 1949, Collette became the first Black musician hired to perform in a nationally broadcast television studio orchestra, appearing on You Bet Your Life. He later gained national recognition as a founding member of the Chico Hamilton Quintet, one of the most prominent West Coast jazz ensembles of the 1950s. In addition to leading his own groups, Collette collaborated extensively with musicians across jazz, popular music, film, and television.
Collette additionally played a significant role in the desegregation of the Los Angeles musicians' union, bringing together Local 47, a union for white musicians, and Local 767, a union for Black musicians in 1953. He was also deeply committed to music education, teaching at multiple Southern California institutions and mentoring younger musicians throughout his career. Collette's professional performing career ended in 1998 after a stroke. However, he continued to compose music for JazzAmerica, a band of teen jazz musicians he co-founded. Collette's career and accomplishments were rewarded with the Lifetime Achievement Award from the American Federation of Musicians and a special commendation from the Los Angeles Jazz Society, along with the legacy of the JazzAmerica program. He passed away in Los Angeles in 2010 at the age of 89.
Scope and Contents
This collection is comprised of personal and professional papers; contracts and business records; musical manuscripts and songbooks; writings; printed ephemera; photographs; and audiovisual and digital media accumulated and maintained by jazz multi-instrumentalist, composer, and educator Buddy Collette. It contains correspondence documenting Collette's personal relationships, collaborations, and professional networks, as well as administrative materials, including American Federation of Musicians contracts, personal agreements, copyright registration files, and financial records. The largest portion of the collection consists of musical works in manuscript form, including original compositions by Collette, arrangements by Collette of works by other composers, and scores and parts by other composers that were retained for performance, study, or reference. These materials appear primarily as manuscript scores, lead sheets, sketches, parts, and incomplete drafts, and include a substantial body of untitled and unidentified pages preserved and organized for access.
The collection also includes creative reference writings, such as poetry sent to Collette by friends and associates, scripts and dramatic texts, and discography-related notes, reflecting Collette's artistic community and interests beyond performance. Printed and ephemeral materials document Collette's public presence through reviews and newspaper clippings, concert and event programs, flyers, posters, and a small set of magazines and publications related to jazz culture and professional affiliations. Photographs, many originally stored in labeled binders, depict Collette with fellow musicians and friends, as well as materials related to his service in the U.S. Navy Reserve band at St. Mary's Pre-Flight School during World War II, alongside unidentified subjects. Audio, audiovisual and digital materials, including reel-to-reel tapes, audio and video cassettes, and CDs, DVDs, and DATs, document studio and master recordings, film and commercial music work, live performances, rehearsals, interviews, educational sessions, and community events, and preserve original labeling that has been transcribed without standardization.
It is important to note that the collection does not document every project, performance, or period of Collette's career in equal depth, and some musical and audiovisual materials lack dates, complete titles, or clear contextual information. In addition, while some materials originated in binders and labeled groupings, select binders were disassembled for preservation; original labels and identifiable groupings were retained where possible.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged in the following series:
Series 1: Correspondence and Personal Papers
Subseries 1.1: Correspondence
Subseries 1.2: Contracts and Business Records
Subseries 1.3: Personal and Biographical Materials
Series 2: Musical Works
Subseries 2.1: Compositions by Buddy Collette
Subseries 2.2: Arrangements by Buddy Collette of Others' Works
Subseries 2.3: Works by Other Composers
Subseries 2.4: Songbooks
Subseries 2.5: Study Materials
Subseries 2.6: Miscellaneous Musical Materials
Series 3: Writings and Creative Works
Series 4: Printed and Ephemeral Materials
Subseries4.1: Newspaper Clippings
Subseries 4.2: Programs and Flyers
Subseries4.3: Magazines and Publications
Subseries 4.4: Posters
Series 6: Audio, Audiovisual and Digital Materials
Subseries 6.1: 1/4" Open Reel Audiotapes
Subseries 6.1.1: 4" Diameter
Sub-Subseries 6.1.2: 5" Diameter
Sub-Subseries 6.1.3: 7" Diameter
Sub-Subseries 6.1.4: 10.5" Diameter
Subseries 6.2: Cassette-Based Media
Sub-Sub-Series 6.2.1: Compact Audio Cassettes
Sub-Sub-Series 6.2.2: VHS(s)
Sub-Sub-Series 6.2.3: VHS-C(s)
Subseries 6.3: Digital Media (Physical Carriers)
Sub-Subseries 6.3.1: CD(s)
Sub-Subseries 6.3.2: DVD(s)
Sub-Subseries 6.3.3: DAT(s)
Related Materials
Collections:
American Federation of Musicians. Local 767 records (Collection 2341). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
League of Allied Arts records (Collection 1856). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
Oral Histories:
Interview of Buddy Collette [oral history transcript] / Steven L. Isoardi, interviewer. UCLA Library Special Collections, Center for Oral History Research interview, 1989. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
Online Images: Please search for "Buddy Collette" on the UCLA Library Digital Collections portal.
Jazz musicians -- California -- Los Angeles; Music -- California -- Los Angeles; African Americans -- California -- Los Angeles; Collette, Cheryl
- Series 1: Correspondence and Personal Papers
  Scope and Contents
  Documents Buddy Collette's personal and professional life through correspondence, administrative records, and biographical materials. Materials reflect Collette's relationships, collaborations, professional obligations, and personal interests.
  Arrangement
  Arranged into three subseries by function and record type.
  - Sub-Series 1.1: Correspondence
    Incoming and outgoing personal and professional correspondence documenting Collette's relationships and professional work.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Correspondence, 1957-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1994-2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sub-Series 1.2: Contracts and Business Records
    Administrative, legal, and financial records, including American Federation of Musicians contracts, personal agreements, copyright registrations, and financial materials.
    Arranged by record type and chronologically within each type.
    - American Federation of Musicians Contracts, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - American Federation of Musicians Contracts, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - American Federation of Musicians Constitution, By-Laws and Policies (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Personal Contracts and Agreements (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Copyright Registration Materials (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Financial Statements (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sub-Series 1.3: Personal and Biographical Materials
    Proposals, contact lists, catalogs, clippings, research materials, and mixed personal documents.
    Grouped by type; original binder groupings retained when identifiable.
    - "All That L.A. Jazz" Proposal (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - The Flute Center Flute Music Catalogs (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Personal Contact Information (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Binder, originally labeled "Letters, reviews, pictures, clippings, etc" (disassembled) (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Binder, labeled "Buddy Collette Jazz History" (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Mixed Personal Documents (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series 2: Musical Works
  Musical manuscripts documenting Buddy Collette's work as a composer, arranger, performer, and educator. Includes compositions, arrangements, works by other composers, songbooks, study materials, and untitled or fragmentary musical materials.
  Arranged into six subseries based on authorship and function.
  - Sub-Series 2.1: Compositions by Buddy Collette
    Manuscript scores, lead sheets, sketches, parts, and drafts composed by Collette.
    Arranged alphabetically by title; formats are interfiled.
    - Addison Street (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Andre (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - April Skies (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Bad Dreams (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - A Ballad for Bill Green, 1994; 1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Bass on Top (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - The Beem Theme (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - A Bit of Basie (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - The Blues (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Blue Sands (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Blues in Torrance, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 12, Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Blues #4 (Box 4, Folder 1, Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Body and Soul (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Border Stop (Box 4, Folder 3, Box 5)
    - The Bridge (Box 4, Folder 4, Box 5, Box 6, Folder 1)
    - The Brush Off (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - California City (Box 4, Folder 6, Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Cal Poly Blues, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - C'est Si Bon, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Change It (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Cheryl Ann (Box 4, Folder 10, Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Crystal (Box 5, Folder 7, Box 7, Folder 1)
    - The Cycle, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Dance of the Bear (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Darling Je Vous Aime Beaucoup, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Domino, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Double Fugue #3 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Eastsiders Theme (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Emaline's Theme (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Fugue #2 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Fugue #2 and #3 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Fugue #4 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Fugue #5 (Box 7, Folders 10)
    - Fun City (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Gauguin (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - George Washington Carver Short Film Music, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Gloria (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Green Dream (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Hamlet, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 5, Box 9, Folder 1)
    - I Hear Bells (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Hunt and Peck (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Impossible Dream (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Inverness (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Irony Theme (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Is it Hard to Come True? (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - It's You (Box 8, Folder 11, Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Jake (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Jazz America Theme (Box 9, Folder 3, Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Jazz by the Bay (Box 9, Folder 4, Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Jazz City Blues (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Jazz for Thousand Oaks (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Jimmy the Cap (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Jungle Pipe, 1956 April 2 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Jus for Rus (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Just Another Day for Love (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - K Abe (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Kelly (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - La Jolla (Box 9, Folder 5, Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Le Conte Blues (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Line for Clarinet and Bass (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Loyola Marymount Theme (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Magali (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Mam' Selle, 1947; 1958 (Box 9, Folder 6, Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Marcell, 1979 November (Box 9, Folder 7, Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Mistress (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Monday Mood (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Monorail, 1956; 1980 (Box 9, Folder 8, Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Mood for Max (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Moulin Rouge, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Goodbye (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - A Nice Day (Box 9, Folder 9, Box 11, Folder 10)
    - A Night at El Camino (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - 9753 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - One for the Air (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - One Note Samba (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Orlando (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Paddi (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Paris Moods (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Pickford Street (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Pigalle, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Point Fermin Suite, 1996 June 6 (Box 6, Folder 5, Box 9, Folder 10, Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Pretorius (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Reunion, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Road Trip, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Room with Skies, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Roshanda, 2007 (Box 12, Folder 12, Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Ruby (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - St. Andrews Place Blues (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Santa Monica (Box 13, Folder 2, Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Santa Tecla (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Selling Boats and All That Fun (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Shatara, 1973; 1996 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - A Short Story, 1996 March 26 (Box 13, Folder 6, Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Singapore Sling, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 7, Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Slappy's Tune (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Sleep (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Soft Touch (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - I Still Love You (Box 13, Folder 11, Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Storybook Kiddles (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Sunset Drive (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Taboo, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - A Taste of Fresh Air (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Tasty Dish (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Theme #4 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - This is Your Day (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Three and Four (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Three and One (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Three Movements for Flute and Harp, 1971; 1977 (Box 15, Folders 8-9)
    - Three Part Fugue, 1965 May 20 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Trauma Movie, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Twelve Tone Blues, 1972 February (Box 14, Folder 7, Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Two Movements for Tenor Sax and Strings for Roger Hogan, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - A Typical Day in the Life of Superwomen, 1983 August (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Vacation Village (Box 14, Folder 8, Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Veda (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - We Are All One People (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Will and Fred (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Will I Ever Fall in Love (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Sub-Series 2.2: Arrangements by Buddy Collette of Others' Works
    Arrangements by Collette of works by other composers.
    Arranged alphabetically by composer, then by title.
    - Bennett, Tony, 1987 July (Box 14, Folder 9, Box 16, Folder 8)
      Songs: I Left My Heart in San Francisco
    - Callender, Red (Box 16, Folder 9)
      Songs: Dolphin Street Blues, Pastel, Skyline
    - Debussy, Claude (Box 16, Folder 10)
      Songs: Clair De Lune
    - De Lloyd and McKaye (Box 16, Folder 11)
      Songs: Now That I Am Here With You
    - Ellington, Duke (Box 14, Folder 10, Box 16, Folder 12)
      Songs: Prelude to a Kiss, Satin Doll
    - Gershwin, George (Box 17, Folders 1-2)
      Songs: From the Opera Porgy and Bess: Oh Bess, Where's My Bess?, I Got Plenty of Nothing, It Ain't Necessarily So, My Man's Gone Now, Summertime, Other songs: Boat That's Leaving, How Long Has This Been Going On, Soon
    - Greer, Jesse (Box 17, Folder 3)
      Songs: Just You Just Me
    - Hefti, Neal (Box 17, Folder 4)
      Songs: Exodus
    - Jobim, Antonio Carlos (Box 17, Folder 5)
      Songs: The Girl from Ipanema, Triste
    - Johnston, Merle (Box 14, Folder 11)
      Songs: Star Dust
    - Leigh, Mitch (Box 14, Folder 12)
      Songs: Impossible Dream
    - Marcus, Wade (Box 17, Folders 6-7)
      Songs: Conversation, Shades of Blue
    - Mingus, Charles (Box 14, Folder 13, Box 17, Folder 8)
      Songs: Bed Spread, Goodbye Porkpie Hat
    - Monk, Thelonious (Box 14, Folder 14, Box 18, Folder 1)
      Songs: Round Midnight
    - Parker, Charlie (Box 18, Folder 2)
      Songs: Donna Lee
    - Raksin, David (Box 18, Folder 3)
      Songs: The Bad and the Beautiful
    - Tizol, Juan (Box 18, Folder 4)
      Songs: Perdido
  - Sub-Series 2.3: Works by Other Composers
    Musical works by other composers retained among Collette's papers.
    - Adams, Anthony (Box 18, Folder 5)
      Songs: Something for Benny
    - Bach, Johann Sebastian (Box 18, Folder 6)
      Songs: Bourree, Courante, Polonaise, Siciliana, Suite II, Sonata III
    - Barroso, Ary (Box 18, Folder 7)
      Songs: Brazil
    - Barone, Mike (Box 18, Folder 8)
      Songs: Medalist
    - Basie, Count (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Song: One O'Clock Jump
    - Berlin, Irving (Box 18, Folder 9, Box 19, Folder 1)
      Songs: Heat Wave, Pretty Girl is Like a Melody
    - Bolling, Claude (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Songs: Irlandaise, Veloce
    - Brown, Garnett (Box 18, Folder 10, Box 19, Folder 2)
      Songs: Belle of the Ball
    - Bruno, Mauro (Box 18, Folder 11)
      Songs: Babass, The Faucet, The Hitch-Hiker, Salutation for Sax Quartet
    - Callender, Red, 1969; 1992 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      Songs: Chula Vista Cris, Primrose Lane
    - Carter, Benny (Box 18, Folder 13)
      Songs: South Side Samba
    - Caymmi, Dori (Box 18, Folder 14)
      Songs: Forever Lover and Friend
    - Chaplin, Charlie (Box 18, Folder 15)
      Songs: Smile
    - Dolphy, Eric (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Drayton, Leslie (Box 6, Folder 8, Box 18, Folder 16)
      Songs: Take a Plunge, Wishful Thinking
    - Duke, Vernon (Box 19, Folder 4)
      Songs: Cabin in the Sky
    - Ellington, Duke (Box 20, Folders 1-2)
      Songs: Black and Tan Fantasy, Brown Penny, Come Sunday, The Creole Love Call, Day Dream, Heaven, Heritage, In a Sentimental Mood, It Don't Mean a Thing, I Let a Song Go Out of My Heart, Sentimental Lady, Smada, Sophisticated Lady, Take the "A" Train, Things Ain't What They Used to Be, Villes Ville is the Place, Man
    - Faith, Percy, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      Songs: On Green Dolphin Street
    - Feyne, Buddy (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Songs: Tuxedo Junction
    - Fischer, Carl (Box 6, Folder 10, Box 19, Folder 5)
      Songs: We'll Be Together Again
    - Gamer, Erroll (Box 21, Folder 1)
      Songs: Misty
    - Golson, Benny (Box 20, Folder 4)
      Songs: Killer Joe
    - Gordon, Irving (Box 20, Folder 5)
      Songs: Unforgettable
    - Gorney, Jay (Box 20, Folder 6)
      Songs: The Bill of Rights
    - Henderson, Bill (Box 20, Folder 7)
      Songs: My How the Time Goes By
    - Herman, Jerry (Box 20, Folder 8)
      Songs: Hello Dolly
    - Hickman, Art (Box 20, Folder 9)
      Songs: Rose Room
    - Hogan, Roger (Box 20, Folder 10)
      Songs: Ballad for Buddy, Theme for Millie, Theme for Rhonda
    - Jordan, Louis (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Songs: Is You Is My Baby
    - Kanner, Harold Irving (Box 20, Folder 11)
      Songs: Ballada, A Touch of Blue
    - Katz, Fred (Box 19, Folders 7-8, Box 20, Folder 12)
      Songs: Bene Hechala, Concerto for Buddy, Elegy for a Critic, Hillel Plotinus Teresa, Hy the Man, Not Really the Blues, To My Buddy, Buddy, The Walker
    - Kissane, Ruth (Box 20, Folder 13)
      Songs: Hurri-Galley, Modallion, November Blues, Winward
    - Lane, Burton (Box 20, Folder 14)
      Songs: Old Devil Moon
    - Lloyd, Charles F. (Box 22, Folder 1)
      Songs: Love Song to a Baby
    - Mancini, Henry (Box 21, Folder 2)
      Songs: Mr. Lucky
    - Matthews, Llew (Box 22, Folder 2)
      Songs: Blues for Fun, Caricature, A Little Jazz, Pumpin' Keys, Return to the Night Song, Shy Moments, Song of Praise, Tales of the 3rd Ear, Thiago
    - McCullough, James (Box 19, Folder 9)
      Songs: Concerto for Alto Flute and Harp, Concerto for Tenor Sax
    - Mills, Verlye (Box 22, Folder 3)
      Songs: Theme from "Lost Love"
    - Mingus, Charles (Box 22, Folder 4)
      Songs: Haitian Fight Song, Nostalgia in Times Square
    - Monk, Thelonious (Box 22, Folder 5)
      Songs: Blue Monk, Straight, No Chaser, Well You Needn't
    - Oakland, Ben (Box 22, Folder 6)
      Songs: I'll Take Romance
    - Porter, Cole (Box 21, Folder 3, Box 22, Folder 7)
      Songs: Don't Fence Me In, Night and Day, What is This Thing Called Love
    - Provost, Heinz (Box 22, Folder 8)
      Songs: Intermezzo
    - Raksin, David (Box 22, Folder 9)
      Songs: Laura
    - Richie, Lionel (Box 22, Folder 10)
      Songs: Ballerina Girl, Endless Love, Three Times a Lady, Truly
    - Ronnell, Ann (Box 22, Folder 11)
      Songs: Willow Weep for Me
    - Schertzinger, Victor (Box 22, Folder 12)
      Songs: Tangerine
    - Shtrum, Haim, 1984 July (Box 22, Folder 13)
      Songs: Rocapriccio
    - Silver, Horace (Box 22, Folder 14)
      Songs: Nica's Dream, Song for my Father
    - Suesse, Dana (Box 22, Folder 15)
      Songs: The Night is Young (And You're So Beautiful)
    - Van Heusen, Jimmy, 1945 August 23 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      Songs: A Friend of Yours
    - Warren, Harry (Box 22, Folder 16)
      Songs: Jeepers Creepers
    - Wiggins, Gerald (Box 23, Folder 1)
      Songs: Sonar
    - Young, Lester (Box 21, Folder 4)
      Songs: Symphony Sid
    - Zimmerman, Harry (Box 23, Folder 2)
      Songs: A Matter of Time
  - Sub-Series 2.4: Songbooks
    Published songbooks and commercially printed scores.
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - The Buddy Collette Songbook, 1985 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Buddy Collette Two Fugues for Piano (Box 23, Folder 3)